appointment-plus.com 2016-05-27

# Appointment-Plus Privacy Policy | Online Scheduling Software Privacy

**1\. Privacy Overview**

StormSource, LLC dba StormSource (“StormSource” or the “Company”) is committed to protecting the privacy of all Client and customer/end-user information. This Privacy Statement describes StormSource’s privacy practices.

StormSource offers a variety of applications and services that are collectively referred to as the “Services.” StormSource collects information from individuals who visit the Company’s Web sites (“Visitors”), individuals who register to use the StormSource application (“Clients”), and individuals who register and/or schedule with Clients’ accounts (“Customers” or “End-users”).

When expressing an interest in obtaining additional information about the Services or registering to use the Services, StormSource requires individuals to provide the Company with personal contact information, such as name, company name, address, phone number, and email address (“Required Contact Information”). When purchasing the Services, StormSource may require individuals to provide the Company with financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, credit card number, and the scope of use within the organization for the Services (“Billing Information”). StormSource may also ask for additional information, such as company annual revenues, number of employees, or industry (“Optional Information”). Required Contact Information, Billing Information, and Optional Information are referred to collectively as “Data About StormSource Clients.”

In the event that StormSource Client utilize the Customer scheduling features of the system, Client may require their own Customers to enter data into the system to facilitate use of the Services. Clients maintain a wide array of options for what types of data may be entered concerning their Customer base (i.e. names, emails addresses, telephone numbers, account numbers, etc). StormSource does not monitor the types of data required, maintained, or stored in the Services by Clients. This type of information is referred to collectively as “Data About Customers” or “Data About Customers/End-users.”

As Clients and Customers navigate the Company’s Web sites, StormSource may collect information through the use of commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies, (“Web Site Navigational Information”). Web Site Navigational Information includes standard information from the Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions taken on StormSource’s sites (such as the StormSource Web pages viewed and the links clicked).

Similarly, in the event that Clients utilize the Customer self-scheduling components of the Services and allow their Customers to access online scheduling, as such Customers navigate the Company’s Web pages, StormSource may also collect information through the use of the Web Site Navigational Information such as standard information from the Web browser (such as browser type and browser language), Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, and the actions taken on StormSource’s sites (such as the StormSource Web pages viewed and the links clicked).

**2\. Use of Information Collected**

The Company uses Data About StormSource Clients only to perform the Services requested. For example, if a staff member is added into a Client account, that staff member’s Data is used only to facilitate the Client’s use of the Services (i.e. to send the staff member an email notice of an appointment, if the Client account is configured to do so). Other than the uses stated in this Statement, StormSource does not use or share Data About Clients for any purpose unless required to do so by law.

The Company uses Data About Customers/End-users only to perform the Services requested. For example, if a Customer is added into a Client account, that Customer’s Data is used only to facilitate the Client’s use of the Services (i.e. to send the Customer an email notice of an appointment, if the Client account is configured to do so). Other than the uses stated in this Statement, StormSource does not use or share Data About Customers/End-users for any purpose unless required to do so by law.

Internally, StormSource employees may be required to access Data About StormSource Clients and/or Data About Customers in order to do their jobs. These employees are limited in number, and are committed to StormSource privacy policies set forth herein. All such employees execute non-disclosure agreements, which provide explicit confidentiality protections. Any employee who violates such privacy and/or security policies is subject to possible termination and civil and/or criminal prosecution.

The Company may use Data About StormSource Clients for limited informational and marketing purposes about the Services. For example, the Company may use Data About StormSource Clients to provide system updates/notices and to discuss interest in the Services and related products and add-ons. This type of informational use is made only to the primary account and billing contacts of the Client, as applicable. Other than limited identification statements such as “Scheduling Powered by StormSource” or “Facebook like StormSource” displayed only on the Customer/End-user self-scheduling pages and system emails, no other type of informational or marketing communication or contact is made or displayed to Customers/End-users.

StormSource uses credit card information solely to check the financial qualifications of prospective Clients and to collect payment for the Services.

StormSource uses Web Site Navigational Information to operate and improve the Company’s Web sites (i.e. www.appointment-plus.com). The Company may also use Web Site Navigational Information alone or in combination with Data About StormSource Clients to provide aggregated information about the Company.

**3\. Web Site Navigational Information**

StormSource uses commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies, to collect information as you navigate the Company’s Web sites (“Web Site Navigational Information”). This section describes the types of Web Site Navigational Information that may be collected on the Company’s Web sites and how this information may be used.

**3.1 Cookies**

StormSource uses cookies to make interactions with the Company’s Web pages easy and meaningful. When Clients and/or Customers visit one of the Company’s Web sites, StormSource’s servers send a cookie to the visitor’s computer. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify an individual. Cookies merely recognize the Web browser. Unless an individual chooses to identify himself/herself to StormSource, such as opening an account or entering login information, individuals remain anonymous to the Company.

If a user of the Services has chosen to identify himself/herself to StormSource, the Company uses session cookies containing encrypted information to allow the Company to uniquely identify such users. Each time such user logs into the Services, a session cookie containing an encrypted, unique identifier that is tied to the user’s account is placed on that user’s browser. These session cookies allow the Company to uniquely identify you when the user is logged into the Services and to process online data transactions and requests. Session cookies are required to use the Services.

**3.2 IP Addresses**

When users visit StormSource’s Web sites, the Company collects the Internet Protocol (“IP”) addresses to track and aggregate non-personal information. For example, StormSource uses IP addresses to monitor the regions from which Clients, Customers, and Visitors navigate the Company’s Web sites and pages.

**4\. Sharing of Information Collected**

StormSource may share Data About StormSource Customers and Data About Customers with the Company’s own service providers to facilitate use of the Services. For example, data center providers may be required for use of the Services. Likewise, Clients may elect to utilize web services and integrations requiring the sharing of data to facilitate use of the Services.

StormSource does not share, sell, rent, or trade any Data About StormSource Clients or Data About Customers with third parties for their promotional purposes.

StormSource may use a third-party service provider to facilitate and manage credit card processing. These credit card service providers are not permitted to store, retain, or use Billing Information except for the sole purpose of credit card processing on the Company’s behalf.

StormSource reserves the right to use or disclose information provided if required by law or if the Company reasonably believes that use or disclosure is necessary to protect the Company’s rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process.

**5\. Security**

StormSource uses robust security measures to protect Data from unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and help ensure the appropriate use of Data. When the Services are accessed using the Internet, Transport Layer Security(TLS) technology protects Customer Data using both server authentication and data encryption. These technologies help ensure that Customer Data is safe, secure, and only available to the Customer to whom the information belongs and those to whom the Customer has granted access. StormSource also implements other advanced technology measures to prevent interference or access from outside intruders. StormSource offers enhanced security features within the Services that permit Clients to configure security settings to the level they deem necessary, such as forced password changes and IP-restrictions. Customers are responsible for maintaining the security and confidentiality of their StormSource usernames and passwords.

**6\. Public Forums, Refer a Friend, and Customer Testimonials**

StormSource may provide bulletin boards, blogs, or chat rooms on the Company's Web sites. Any personal information you choose to submit in such a forum may be read, collected, or used by others who visit these forums, and may be used to send you unsolicited messages. StormSource is not responsible for the personal information you choose to submit in these forums.

Customers and Visitors may elect to use the Company's referral program to inform friends about the Company's Web sites. When using the referral program, the Company requests the friend's name and email address. StormSource will automatically send the friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the Company's Web sites. StormSource does not store this information.

StormSource posts a list of Customers and testimonials on the Company's Web sites that contain information such as Customer names and titles. StormSource obtains the consent of each Customer prior to posting any information on such a list or posting testimonials.

**7\. Telephone Monitoring**

As part of StormSource customer service assurance practice, telephone conversations over phones may be monitored or recorded as a part of normal business operations. Monitored or recorded calls will be used for quality assurance and training purposes.

**8\. Changes to this Privacy Statement**

StormSource reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement. StormSource will provide notification of the material changes to this Privacy Statement through the Company’s Web sites and/or accounts at least thirty (30) business days prior to the change taking effect.

**9\. Contacting Us**

Questions regarding this Privacy Statement should be directed to StormSource Privacy by mailing to: StormSource, LLC, Attn: Legal Department, 15300 N. 90th Street, Suite 100, Scottsdale, AZ 85260.
